Okay, we are back on github.com except
this time we are now logged in. Um, so
you should see a screen somewhat like
this. Um, the important thing is this
big green button over here that says
new. We are going to be creating a new
repository. What is a repository? Well,
a repository is defined as a place,
building or receptacle where things are
or may be stored. Um, and in this case,
the thing that is being stored is our
code. So, we're going to hit this new
button here.
And now we need to give it a name. I'm
going to call it demo repo. Um,
but you can call it whatever you want.
Um, and then you can give it a
description. I'm going to say
demonstrate
setting
up a code repo. Okay. Now, you can
choose a visibility. So, there are two
options here. There's public and that's
anyone on the internet can see it. They
won't necessarily be able to edit it,
but they can see it. Um, and then
there's private. So, there's some things
to consider when you are making this
decision. Like, for example, um, if you
make it public, future employers could
see, um, some of the projects you've
done and they can look at the code and
it can help them know if they want to
hire you, can help you get an interview.
Um, so maybe you want to set it public.
Um, on the other hand, if you set it
public, um, anyone on the internet can
see your code. So, for example, um I'm
embarrassed to admit that at the
beginning of my programming career, I
wrote this nice website. It had this
part in my code that needed to be kept
secret. It was a key, a security key,
and I pushed it to a public repository,
which meant everyone on the internet
could see the secret key. So, had to
take it down, change the key, repush it.
Um, so if you're starting out and you're
not planning to share it with anyone
while you're working on learning
security practices, you may want to
choose private. Um, but on the other
hand, if you want your employers to know
about a project or other people to be
able to see what's going on, you might
want to choose public. In this case, I'm
going to leave this as public. Okay. The
next part, and this is very important,
is you will want to click add a readme
file. What a readme file does is it lets
you describe your project. The other
thing it does is it makes it easier to
work with GitHub desktop. So, we're
going to add a readme file. Um, and then
we're going to come here and hit create
repository. And it's going to think for
a minute. Um, but once it's done, you
should see this screen. And you have now
successfully created your own code
repository.